Jerissa Lumansoc

(206)214-6751 JerissaLumansoc@gmail.com LinkedIn.com/in/JerissaLumansoc JeriLuma.GitHub.io

Web Developer adept in collaborating with product/business, UI/UX, and development teams. Experience coaching and mentoring other developers. Passionate for learning new technology and developing skills. Demonstrate programming expertise, analytical thinking, creativity and attention to details. Ability to plan logical solutions for programming challenges.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Javascript
- AngularJS 1.X
- Karma Test Runner
- Jasmine
- HTML

- CSS
- SASS
- Angular Material
- JQuery
- D3

- Adobe Creative Suite
- C#
- Java
- MySQL
- SQL

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Optum | Application Developer II | Bothell, WA

2015 - 2017

Optum is a health services and innovation company under UnitedHealth Group. Analyzed business requirements and functional designs to lead Javascript code design and development.

- Coached and mentored less experienced developers to learn AngularJS 1.X and resolve UI issues, optimizing effective teamwork to complete work.
- Collaborated with product, business, UI/UX, QA, and other developers under Agile processes, to deliver high quality applications, exceeding user expectations to production.
- Ensured company coding standards through code scans, code reviews, and unit tests, strengthening quality and functionality of business-critical applications.

CashVue | Front End Web Developer Intern | Seattle, WA

2015 - 2015

CashVue is a startup developing cloud accounting software for businesses. Independently learned the Angular 1.X framework to develop a dynamic application for financial data.

- Developed a responsive administrative user settings page to be use for version 1.0 of CashVue's MVP, which resulted in an interactive list to edit, add, and delete users.
- Utilized open sourced projects for added features, such as tables, graphs, and toolkits, to leverage UI functionality.

Sno-King Junior Golf | Web Developer | Seattle WA

2014 - 2015

Designed web development project to manage and share golf materials between the coach and players.

- Leveraged Wordpress for content and user management, further enhancing features.
- Developed a customized Wordpress theme based on UI mockups to achieve a pixel perfect UI.

RELATED PROJECTS

Plan My Date | INFO 320: Information Needs, Searching, and Presentation | University of Washington, Information School, Seattle, WA

An individual project to create a search web application to plan date ideas, such as food and events.

- Achieved 1st in INFO 320 course competition for search applications.
- Designed a flat UI, allowing for flexible and faceted searching.
- Leveraged Google Places API and Eventful API to suggest date ideas.

Building Search / Web Infrastructure | INFO 344: Web Tools and Development | University of Washington, Information School, Seattle, WA

A back-end web development course individual project to understand information architecture.

- Designed a quick suggestive search UI and programmed a web crawler with admin interface.
- Utilized Amazon Web Services and MS Azure to store search results data.

EDUCATION

B.S. Informatics: Information Architecture and Human-Computer Interaction, Minor in Mathematics University of Washington, Information School, Seattle, WA